#### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

Kate is a **dedicated** and **result-oriented** analyst with experience in **business/financial analysis**, **data validation** and **reporting**. Apart from possessing exceptional **analytical** and **problem-solving** skills, she is a great **team player** with strong **communication** and **presentation** skills. Also, she has a **global perspective** gained from extensive international travel experience.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Language: Business Intelligence: Databases: SQL, Advanced Excel, VBA Power BI, Tableau, Stata, SAS, Eviews, Bloomberg Microsoft SQL Server, MS Access

#### **EXPERTISE**

- ✓ Data Analysis
- ✓ Data Modeling
- ✓ Reporting
- ✓ SQL Ad hoc Analysis

- ✓ Business & Functional Requirement
- ✓ Financial Modeling
- ✓ Data Validation and Testing
- ✓ Marketing Research

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

### Client Advisor, Royal Bank of Canada

Mar 2019-present

- Solid track record in relationship management by achieving 3.5% total solutions rate and maintaining high performance in the branch
- Supported management decision through weekly client analysis and dashboard design
- Demonstrated enthusiasm in the banking sector and strong ability to learn new products efficiently

#### Analyst, EDPYPF Services Inc.

Feb2018-Feb2019

- Analyzed industry trends and customer data in SQL database and validated the data integrity gaps
- Prepared ad hoc and ongoing Tableau reports for clients as well as demonstrated POC with self-service BI tool
- Designed and developed monthly financial income statement report automation process
- Summarized the method to resolve duplication issue in data warehouse

### Analyst (Co-op), Retail Measurement Service, The Nielsen Company

Sep 2013-Feb 2014

- Proficiently used Advanced Excel and Nielsen Answers to conduct in-depth marketing research
- Generated industry analysis and competitive analysis for clients in a team environment
- Performed data mining under tight timelines while maintaining attention to detail

# Intern, Report Analyst, Corporate Finance, Agricultural Bank of China

Jul 2012-Aug 2012

- Conducted customer data quality control to fix quality issue such as name and outstanding credit
- Enhanced VBA to identify and analyze key ratios (Cash Flow, LTV ratio) for credit reports
- Liaised with clients to build loyalty through visiting companies and attending business dinners

# **EDUCATION**

•	Master of Arts in Business Economics, Wilfrid Laurier University, Waterloo, Canada	Sep 2015 - Oct 2017
•	Master of Science in Quantitative Finance, <b>Tilburg University</b> , Tilburg, Holland	Aug 2014 - Aug 2015
•	Bachelor of Economic in Finance, Sun Yat-sen University, Guangzhou, China	Sep 2010 - Jun 2014
•	Exchange Certificate, University of Queensland, Brisbane, Australia	Feb 2013 - July 2013

# **INTERESTS**

Professional Violinist - First Class Honours with Distinction in Violin Performance